# Evan S. Kovanis



15565 Swiss Creek Lane Cupertino, CA 95014 Tel (805) 452-0994 Fax (408) 693-3727

Email <u>Evan@ZeidmanConsulting.com</u>
Website <u>www.ZeidmanConsulting.com</u>

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Evan Kovanis is a research engineer at Zeidman Consulting. He has developed embedded firmware, GUI software, RF hardware, database application software, and ASIC verification code. Evan is certified in the use of CodeSuite®. He holds a bachelor's degree in Computer Engineering from the University of California Santa Barbara.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### 01/2012 - present: Zeidman Consulting - Research Engineer

- Runs CodeSuite® and analyzes results for software IP litigation
- Writes expert reports for software IP litigation
- Performs research on patents and trade secrets
- · Writes claim charts for patent infringement analysis
- Develops software analysis tools

### 03/2011 - 12/2011: Smiths Corporation - Systems Engineer

- Authored and contributed to technical white papers on topics such as transient voltages in an RF environment, the effects of undesired intermodulation, and Ethernet cable development and design
- Technical liaison between customers and the sales and engineering teams in new and existing RF, AC, Data, and DC projects
- Provided RF systems engineering expertise and support to customers and the sales team during development and launch of RF products
- Developed MS Windows Application for report generation and management of SQL database
- Served as the company's principle representative to the Antenna Interface Standards Group committee and as an AISG director

#### 05/2006 - 03/2011: Smiths Corporation - RF/Digital Design Engineer

- Principle developer of a unique firmware solution, hardware, and GUI test env. For an AISG protocol based communication system
- Developed code in C, C++, as well as C#. Involved in all aspects of product design, from board layout to software verification
- Lead engineer in a C# multi-threaded control system; designing the GUI and control logic for a new surge test facility
- Managed project flow and performed design of RF surge suppression devices from concept through prototype and into release

### 01/2005 – 09/2005: Fulcrum Microsystems - ASIC Verification Engineer (Contract Position)

- Designed and contributed to the Java based test bench for a 10 Gigabit per port, 24 port Ethernet chip called Focal Point
- Also designed and wrote modules to verify the SERDES, EPL, Management, JTAG, SCAN, and XAUI portions of this ASIC
- Wrote Java, Perl, and Verilog and also worked closely with PCI-Express in verifying the stand alone EPL

### 11/2004 – 12/2004: Energro Inc. - Embedded Device Programmer / Test Technician (Contract Position)

- Developed C for a PIC micro-controller using internal DAC and ADC functionality to build a closed feedback control circuit
- Debugged and implemented an automated test system using LabView and discrete components including muxes and decoders

### 07/2003 - 10/2003: Ccom Solutions - Software Engineer

Updated business software using Javascript, VB Script, HTML, and Java Networking

#### **LEGAL CONSULTING**

#### 7/2015 - present: Oracle America v. Google

Law Firm: Orrick, Herrington & Sutcliffe

Client: Oracle America

Court: U.S. District Court. Northern District of California

Case: C 10-03561 WHA

Software copyright infringement of Java API packages

• Analyzed and compared source code.

## 12/2014 - 7/2015: NVIDIA Corporation v. Samsung and Qualcomm

Law Firm: Orrick, Herrington & Sutcliffe

Client: NVIDIA Corporation

Court: United States International Trade Commission

Investigation: 337-TA-932

- Alleged patent infringement of graphics hardware and software.
- Read patents, analyzed software and hardware, reviewed hardware and software specifications.
- Wrote expert report.
- Testified in deposition.
- Testified at trial.

### 11/2014 - present: Iconics, Inc. v. Simone Massaro, BaxEnergy GmbH, BaxEnergy Italia S.R.L, et. al.,

Law Firm: Burns & Levinson LLP Law Firm: Orrick, Herrington & Sutcliffe

Client: BaxEnergy

Court: United States District Court, District of Massachusetts

Case: 11-11526-DPW

- Alleged copyright infringement of energy plant management software.
- Wrote declaration.

### 11/2013 – 9/2014: United Services Automobile Association v. Mitek Systems

Law Firm: Wilson Sonsini Goodrich & Rosati / Scheper Kim & Harris

Client: Mitek Systems

Court: U.S. District Court, Western District of Texas, San Antonio Division

Case: SA-12-CA-0282-FB

- Alleged trade secret misappropriation of mobile banking software.
- Alleged patent infringement of mobile banking software.
- Analyzed software and examined specifications.
- Assisted with writing expert reports.

### 8/2012 - 4/2015: Round Rock Research v. SanDisk

Law Firm: Desmarais

Client: Round Rock Research

Court: U.S. District Court. District of Delaware

Case: 12-569 (SLR)

- Alleged patent infringement of flash memory devices.
- Analyzed hardware and firmware and examined specifications.
- Assisted with writing expert reports.

### 8/2012 - 4/2015: SanDisk v. Round Rock Research

Law Firm: Desmarais

Client: Round Rock Research

Court: U.S. District Court, Northern District of California

Case: 1-cv-05243-RS

- Alleged patent infringement of flash memory devices.
- Analyzed hardware and firmware and examined specifications.
- Assisted with writing expert reports.

### 7/2012 - 5/2013: Kenneth C. Henry v. Petrolink v. Digital Well File

Law Firms: Wright & Close, Martin, Disiere, Jefferson & Wisdom

Client: neutral expert

Court: District Court of Harris County, Texas, 133rd Judicial District

Case: 2010-08178

- Alleged copyright infringement
- Alleged trade secret theft.
- Compared software source code using CodeMatch.
- Assisted with writing expert reports.

### 7/2012 – 6/2013: Elan Microelectronics v. Pixcir Microelectronics

Law Firm: Alston & Bird LLP Client: Elan Microelectronics

Court: United States District Court, District of Nevada

Case: 2:10-cv-00014-GMN-(PAL)Alleged patent infringement.

# 1/2012 - 5/2015: Intellectual Ventures v. Altera, Microsemi, Lattice Semiconductor, And Xilinx

Law Firm: Desmarais LLP Client: Intellectual Ventures

Court: U.S. District Court, District of Delaware

Case: C.A. No. 10-1065-LPS

- · Case was settled.
- Alleged patent infringement of FPGA and ASIC integrated circuits
- Examined schematics and Verilog code.
- Assisted with writing expert reports.

# 1/2012 - 6/2014: ThinkOptics v. Nintendo of America, et al.

Law Firm: Nix Patterson & Roach LLP

Client: ThinkOptics

Court: United States District Court, Eastern District Of Texas, Tyler Division

Case: 6:2011cv00454

• Case was settled.

Alleged patent infringement.

### 1/2012 – 9/2012: E-Micro Corporation v. Google, et al.

Law Firm: Nix Patterson & Roach LLP

Client: E-Micro

Court: United States District Court, Eastern District Of Texas, Tyler Division

Case: 6:11-CV-465 (JDL)

• Alleged patent infringement.

# 1/2012 - 7/2013: Robin Antonick v. Electronic Arts

Law Firm: Keker & Van Nest LLP

Client: Electronic Arts

Court: United States District Court, Northern District of California

Case: 3:11-cv-01543-CRB (EDL)

- Contract dispute
- Alleged copyright infringement.
- Examined source code and binary code.
- Compared software binary code and source code using BitMatch and CodeMatch.
- Assisted with writing expert reports.

#### 1/2012 - 7/2012: Brocade v. A10 Networks

Law Firms: Orrick, Herrington & Sutcliffe; McDermott, Will & Emery

Client: Brocade

Court: U.S. District Court, Northern District Of California, San Jose Division

Case: C 10-03428 LHK (PSG)

- Alleged copying of software for network controllers.
- Examined source code.

#### **EDUCATION**

B.S. Computer Engineering (Honors), University of California, Santa Barbara, 2004

T.E.C. (Technology Entrepreneurship Certificate), University of California, Santa Barbara, 2004

#### PAPERS AND PRESENTATIONS

- 1. Zeidman, Bob and Kovanis, Evan, "Round 2: Did Oracle Overlook the Smoking Gun in its Case against Google?" *IPWatchdog* (<a href="www.ipwatchdog.com">www.ipwatchdog.com</a>), July 11, 2012.
- 2. Kovanis, Evan and Zeidman, Bob, "Did Oracle Overlook the Smoking Gun in its Case against Google?" *IPWatchdog* (<a href="www.ipwatchdog.com">www.ipwatchdog.com</a>), June 26, 2012.

#### **AWARDS & MEMBERSHIP**

- National Society, Collegiate Scholars. Member (2001 2004) Officer (2002 2003)
- Dean's List Scholar Award. (Winter, Spring 2003; Fall, Winter, Spring 2004)
- Center for Engineering and Entrepreneurship Management. Member (2002 2004)
- Student Entrepreneur's Association. Member (2002 2004)

### SPECIAL KNOWLEDGE AND SKILLS

- Embedded systems
- FPGA and CPLD design
- Java Database Connectivity (JDBC)
- Java Swing
- LAN Intercom
- Microprocessor design
- Operating Systems:
  - Linux
  - UNIX
  - Windows
- PCB layout
- Programming Languages:
  - C
  - C++
  - C#
  - SQL
  - Java
  - JavaScript
  - Perl
  - HTML
  - Verilog
  - VHDL
- RISC processor architecture
- Remote Method Invocation (RMI)
- Verilog
- XML